DELICIOUS IN DUNGEON
《迷宫饭》
Really, though.
天啊 真是的
There's nothing more horrifying than black magic.
黑魔法未免也太可怕了
Was bringing this person back worth going down that path?
为了让那个人复活 值得做到这种地步吗？
It's only natural for Shuro to be furious.
修洛先生会生气也是理所当然的
Using shady methods like that to resurrect someone?
就算用那种不正当的手段让人复活
That's just risky.
只会有风险不是吗？
Letting her stay dead would've been better for her--
让她直接死去 对她本人也比较…
Enough!
别说了！
I understand your point,
我懂你的意思了
so please stop.
所以不要再说了
Sorry.
抱歉
Shuro, deep down, you probably know
修洛先生 你在心里也察觉到了吧？
that if you were in his shoes, you'd have done the same thing.
如果你遇到同样的状况 也会采取相同的手段
I know that!
我自己明白！
But his attitude is just too much!
虽然明白 但他的态度实在是太过分了！
We fed on monsters!
我们吃了魔物大餐！
I think my favorite is the Red Dragon because of the memories.
最印象深刻的应该是 充满回忆的炎龙吧
Check this out! It's a monster sword!
快看！是魔物剑！
We may have used black magic, but you won't tell anyone, right?
虽然我们用了黑魔法 但修洛应该不会说出去吧
Anyway, I have no idea what's going on in your head.
总之我完全不懂你在想什么
I doubt I'll ever understand.
我也不觉得会懂
So I can't help you.
所以我无法帮你
Laios! Senshi!
莱欧斯！先西！
We've got trouble!
糟了！
A group of monsters is attacking the cooking crew and…
有一群魔物冲入调理组那里…
What have you done?
你做了什么？
I told him everything that's happened so far.
我把至今发生的所有事都跟他说了
Everything?!
全部？
I thought that Shuro would understand.
我想说修洛应该会谅解
Shuro's the last person you should have told!
不管怎么想 都最不能跟他说吧！
I figured.
我同意
Is this on me?
难道是我的错吗？
Did I make the wrong call?
是我判断错误吗？
Don't beat yourself up.
请打起精神吧
He's just a little tired.
他是因为有些累才会这样
I have a lot of respect for him.
我很尊敬他
He's helped me out countless times on our adventures.
在冒险途中都不知道被他救了几次
He told me tales of foreign lands
对只了解故乡的国家和这座小岛的我
when all I've known was my homeland and this island.
他分享了很多异国的故事
Shuro's always been cool-headed and smart.
修洛是个常保冷静 头脑又好的人
For him to explode like that,
那样的他竟气成这样
I must've really messed up.
我应该是做了很严重的事吧
It'd be a shame if our friendship ended like this…
虽然我们的友情就此结束的话 我会非常伤心…
Harpies.
哈比
This is getting us nowhere.
这样下去没完没了
Asebi!
马醉木！
Let's go, you three!
你们三人都跟我走！
Laios told Shuro everything that's happened so far.
莱欧斯那家伙将所有一切 都跟修洛全盘托出了
What? Is that why the air is so tense?
什么？所以气氛才那么糟？
Shuro's furious.
修洛火冒三丈
What do we do?
怎么办？
If the story gets to the surface, we…
要是那件事被地表的人知道 我们…
I know! I know, but…
我知道！我明白啦 但是…
It looks like the ninjas are handling things just fine.
忍者那边看起来比较没什么问题
Anyway, who else knows?
总而言之 还有谁知道？
Four people for now.
现在有四人
Shuro and two of his retainers,
修洛和他手下的两个女人
and that curly-haired guy.
加上那个卷毛男
He's the guy whose party was wiped out by Treasure Bugs, right?
他不是曾被宝物虫搞到队伍全灭吗？
What's he doing here?
怎么会在这里？
Who knows?
谁知道？
Maybe he's after whoever stole their loot and food.
可能在找偷了战利品或粮食的某人吧
W-We have to clear that up!
要解开误会才行！
The loot was just Treasure Bugs and the food was drenched and ruined!
战利品其实只是宝物虫 粮食是被水淹坏的啦！
You idiot!
笨蛋！
The bigger problem is your use of black magic.
更重要的问题是黑魔法吧
Shuro is angry, but he's not a concern.
虽然修洛在生气 但不是大问题
He's just ticked off we put Falin in danger.
他只是在气我们将法琳置于危险之中
But I'm not sure about the others.
不过其他人就难说了
By the way, how much evidence is left of you using black magic?
顺便问一下 你还留了多少 使用了黑魔法的证据？
The magic circle got erased by the Cleaners,
魔法阵已经被清道夫清除了
but there might be trouble if they check Falin's body and my staff too closely.
要是法琳的身体跟魔杖被彻底调查 事态可能会不太妙
We need to torch your staff right now!
那现在就把魔杖给烧了！
Wait a minute!
等一下！
If they're already onto us that much, burning my staff won't make a difference.
要是他们已经怀疑到那个地步 那我们做什么都没用啦
Huh?
什么？
Over there, look!
那边 快看啊！
What's that monster?
那个魔物是什么？
A Harpy?
哈比？
No.
不对
What?
什么？
How?
为什么？
Falin…
法琳…
It can't be.
不会吧
No.
不可能
What on earth?
那到底是什么啊？
It's so cool!
超帅的！
But it's a little too greedy.
但有点太贪心了吧
It's got wings, feathers, and scales too.
居然有翅膀、羽毛跟鳞片
Falin!
法琳！
Do you recognize me?
你认得我吗？
Knock it off, Marcille!
别说了 玛露希尔！
Falin!
法琳！
-Holm! Rin! Prepare for battle! -Falin!
-霍尔姆！铃！准备战斗！ -法琳
-R-Right! -Right.
-好！ -好
-Laios, Shuro! What's the plan? -Falin!
-莱欧斯、修洛！要怎么做？ -法琳！
Tell us what to do!
给我们指示！
Inutade, don't hurt her!
犬蓼 别伤害她！
Try to restrain her!
制伏对方就好！
Uh. Huh?
嗯 什么？
No, Young Master. Run--
不行 少爷 快逃…
So, I need to restrain her.
所以我得活捉她
Restrain her without hurting her.
在不让她受伤的情况下抓到
Restrain her without hurting her?
要抓她 但不能让她受伤？
Can you do it, Holm?
你能做到吗？霍尔姆
Y-Yeah.
可以
All right.
好
Come out.
出来吧
Falin!
法琳！
A-An Undine?
水元素？
Are you controlling that?
那是你在操纵的吗？
Please make it stop!
拜托 让水元素停下来！
She's just confused.
她只是陷入了混乱啊
Give me a break.
给我适可而止
You don't care how many people die
你们为了保护自己重要的人
if you can protect someone dear to you, is that it?
不管要牺牲多少人都不在乎吗？
That thing isn't "her."
那已经不是你们认识的“她”了
It's just a monster!
就只是只魔物！
Ludeloes Arnbite.
鲁底罗艾斯安比底
Oh, Marillier…
天啊 玛莉莉艾…
It can even cast spells?
那家伙居然也能咏唱魔法？
No, Kuro!
不要啊 小黑！
Don't, you fool! Stay hidden!
住手 你这笨蛋！给我躲好！
Falin…
法琳…
Out of my way!
闪开！
Andarses Orbis!
安达赛斯欧尔毕斯！
Monsters are dangerous.
魔物毕竟是危险生物
Damn it, Kensuke!
可恶 剑助！
Never trust a monster…
你终究是个魔物…
Forgive me, Falin.
对不起 法琳
I wish I could've switched places with you.
多希望我能跟你交换
My big brother, Laios.
莱欧斯哥哥
Falin!
法琳！
The lungs, kidneys,
肺、肾
and the heart!
心脏！
I'm going to die.
我要死了
Can you stand?
站得住吗？
I'm sorry I hesitated.
抱歉 我犹豫了
You're right.
你说得对
My sister's soul
我妹妹的灵魂
is probably under the control of the lord of the dungeon now.
现在应该在迷宫之主的支配下
But if we kill her, the lunatic magician will show up again.
但要是杀了她 狂乱魔术师一定又会出现
For now, we need to get out of here.
现在必须远离这里
But--
但是…
Falin!
法琳！
Hey!
等等！
You monster!
你这怪物！
Ludeloes Ejectulm Hemtum.
鲁底罗艾斯艾杰克图姆海姆图姆
This spell…
那个咒文…
Everyone, stay close to me!
大家 快来我身边！
Essiet!
艾西艾！
She might return.
她可能还会回来
Let's get the wounded inside the barrier.
让受伤的人去结界避难吧
And the dead…
死人的话…
What should we do?
我们该怎么办？
I'll resurrect them.
我会复活他们
I can't revive everyone, though.
虽然没办法让所有人活过来
Should I gather the bodies?
需要把尸体集中吗？
No, don't move them.
不行 别动他们
We can't waste a drop of shed blood.
不能浪费流出来的任何一滴血
Where's the monster?!
魔物在哪？
It bolted. We're safe now.
逃走了喔 已经没事了
Who's next?
下一位是谁？
Wait.
等等
Bring back that woman first.
先复活那位吧
Why me?
为什么是我？
You seemed to be a powerful mage.
我认为舞鹤小姐是厉害的术师
So I thought you could use healing and resurrection magic.
可能会治疗或使用复活术
He can't heal everyone alone.
他无法独自治疗全部的人
You helped us get here, so this is the least we can do.
而且一路下来 我们也受了你很多帮助 这是该做的
So now I owe you.
看来我欠了人情
My guess is you're after a different spell.
反正你的目的应该是别的魔法吧
Never mind.
算了
Let us get this done quickly.
快点解决吧
Um, I can use basic resurrection magic too.
那个 我也会简单的复活术
No.
住手
Don't you lay a finger on them.
不准你动那些人一根手指
I can't let you use any more black magic.
我不会再让你用黑魔法
I-I wouldn't do that.
我才不会用那种东西
Then what was that?
那你告诉我那是什么
Why did she look like that?
为什么她会变成那样？
It's because you used the Dragon's flesh and black magic on her!
不就是因为你使用龙肉 施加黑魔法才变那样吗？
No! That can't be!
不对！不可能！
The magic didn't have that kind of power.
那类的魔法才没有那种力量！
B-But it's possible that
不过有可能的是
the Red Dragon's soul was under some spell.
炎龙的灵魂被人施了某种魔法
And Falin's soul merged with the Dragon's,
使法琳的灵魂跟龙的灵魂混合
and the lunatic magician transformed her into that creature.
经狂乱魔术师改造才会变成那样
Shuro?
修洛？
I'm handing Marcille over to the elves of the west.
我会把这家伙交给西方精灵
I can't kill that thing.
我杀不了那生物
But I can't let it roam free either.
但也不能就这样放着不管
I want to free her soul from the dungeon
我希望至少将她的灵魂从迷宫解放
and let her rest in peace at least.
让她能安息
But…
怎么这样？
The elves will know how to do that.
精灵应该知道怎么做
Confess everything to the elves of the west.
你得在西方精灵面前 交代整件事情的原委
No, Shuro.
别那样 修洛
There has to be another way.
一定还有其他方法
Give me a break!
别开玩笑了！
What have you been doing until now?
你们至今到底做了什么？
Another way?
其他方法？
What's your plan?
你打算怎么做？
Are you going to keep resurrecting her
难道要用各种魔物的肉不断尝试复活
with different monster parts until she's back to normal?
直到她变回原样吗？
Go on, tell me!
你说啊！
What are you going to do?
你到底要怎么做？
You have an idea, don't you?
你不是有想法吗？
Tell me!
那就说啊！
We'll defeat the lunatic magician!
我们要打败狂乱魔术师！
That Red Dragon was clearly following orders.
那只炎龙明显是被下令才行动
Who else but the magician who created this dungeon could command it?
能做到此事的 只有建造这座迷宫的魔术师
So, we'll take down the magician and rewrite his orders!
那我们就打倒他 覆写他的命令就好了！
I'm not familiar with this sort of thing,
虽然我不清楚详情
but Marcille should know how!
但我相信玛露希尔做得到！
That's why I won't let you take her!
所以我不会把她交给你！
I've had enough!
你别闹了！
Are you really going to use black magic to fix a problem caused by black magic?
你想要用黑魔法 来解决黑魔法造成的问题？
Why don't you start taking things seriously for once?
你稍微认真思考行不行？
Uh… sorr--
那个 对不…
It's true I'm not the most skilled,
确实我的实力没有很高超
and you're stronger than most adventurers.
你也比大多数的冒险者还强
But here's what I know.
不过只有这件事我能清楚声明
We've been getting proper meals three times a day
一天好好吃三餐
and good sleep too.
并且睡饱的我们
That makes us more serious than you!
比你还要认真多了！
Listen to me!
给我听好！
We will take down the lunatic magician and rescue Falin, no matter what!
我们会打倒狂乱魔术师 然后一定会救出法琳！
Shuro, you go back to the surface.
修洛 你回地表吧
Eat, bathe, and rest!
然后吃饭、洗澡、睡觉！
Huh? What was that?
什么？你说啥？
Shut up!
吵死了！
The fight isn't over yet.
不是还没分出胜负吗？
If that's your plan, I have one of my own.
你那么想的话 我也有我的想法
Plan?
想法？
Laios!
莱欧斯！
Listen up.
听好了
For a long time now,
我从很久以前
I couldn't stand your guts.
就不擅长跟你相处
Because you were thoughtless, dense,
因为你既粗枝大叶又迟钝
and always had the worst timing!
还不会看气氛！
Hey, tell me more about those foreign lands!
告诉我更多外国的事嘛！
Are you two eating together? Count me in!
你们两个约好要吃饭？我也要去！
We're friends now, right?
我们已经是朋友了 对吧？
It was even worse because you meant no harm!
而且你没有恶意 所以更难应付！
Why don't I just end you here,
我要在这里杀了你
take Marcille, and--
带走玛露希尔…
Well, you should've told me sooner!
那你早点说啊！
Why were you keeping quiet until now
为何以前都不说
if you couldn't stand me and thought I was dense and had terrible timing?
你其实觉得我很难相处 迟钝又不会看气氛？
I was dropping hints that most people would've picked up on!
我已经用一般人 早就会注意到的方式告诉你了！
You should've made more of an effort to notice!
你也稍微努力 试着察觉啦！
How could I?
怎么察觉？
You were the first friend I made on this island,
你是我在这座岛第一个交到的朋友
and I was too excited to realize!
所以我可是高兴得不得了！
See, that's another thing I can't stand about you!
你的那一点我也很讨厌！
You act all honest
一副就自己最诚实正直的样子！
but end up stressing people out!
给别人带来压力！
How was I supposed to know?
那种事我怎么知道啊？
You never speak up and you don't even eat!
什么也不说 什么也不吃
What's the point of having a mouth?
你长嘴巴的意义在哪？
Shut up, you moron!
闭嘴 笨蛋！
You haven't put in half the effort Marcille has.
你的努力连玛露希尔的一半都不到
We don't have time for this.
现在不是做这种事的时候吧
It's a childish squabble.
真是幼稚的吵架
I must have raised him wrong.
是我教育失败了
Seven dead, including myself,
算上我 共有七人死亡
one in critical condition, and three missing.
一名重伤者 三名状况不明者
The gnome and I will resurrect them, but we're low on blood.
我跟地精可以一起复活其他人 但我们缺血
Senshi, can you gather the scattered ingredients?
先西 可以帮我收集散乱的食材吗？
Sure.
好
I can use basic resurrection magic too.
我也会简单的复活术
You stay out of this.
你别插手此事
Heal the wounded and find the missing.
你去治疗伤患跟找寻失踪的人
If you try anything suspicious, I'll cut you down on the spot.
要是敢用奇怪的魔法 我就当场砍了你
See, Shuro?
怎么样？修洛
Right now, I'm better fed than you are.
果然还是在迷宫吃饭了的我
That's why I'm stronger!
比较强！
D-Damn it.
可恶
It's good.
好吃
Young Master, we've resurrected everyone.
少爷 复活完了
When do you wish to depart?
什么时候出发呢？
No, prepare the return magic.
不 准备回归魔法吧
We're heading back up.
我们要回地面
Are you sure?
确定吗？
Asebi is still missing.
马醉木行踪不明耶
She probably ran off.
她是逃走了吧
Let her be.
不用管她
Please forgive our inadequacy.
请原谅我们的无力
No.
不
You did your best.
你们尽力了
Thank you.
谢谢
I'm sorry for dragging you into this.
抱歉拖你们下水
I'm returning to my homeland.
我会回国
I'll never set foot on this island again.
不再回这座岛
I'll report what happened to the Lord of the Island.
关于这次发生的事 我会向岛主发出警告
I see.
这样啊
I wish I could've returned with Falin.
我本想和法琳一起回去
What was her answer to your proposal?
她对求婚的回复是什么？
I don't know.
不知道
She said she needed time to think about it.
她说需要时间思考
I was waiting for her answer.
我本来在等她的回复
There's no woman more fascinating than her.
没有比她更充满魅力的女性了
I loved her voice, the way she thought,
我爱她的声音、她的想法
and her smile.
还有她的笑容
But I never actually brought any of this up with her.
其实我还没有跟她说过这些话
I wish I had told her sooner.
要是能早点说就好了
Wait, so he just popped the question out of nowhere?
等等 他突然就求婚了吗？
That's scary.
好可怕
From where he comes from, it's normal.
他就是活在那种世界的人
I see. Well, I'll pass on your words to Falin.
原来如此 我会转达给法琳的
That's the part about you
你的那种性格啊
that I envy.
让我好嫉妒
Kabru, you were a big help.
喀布尔 你帮了大忙
I didn't do much.
这没什么
My attack ended up being useless.
我的攻击一点用也没有
No, it helped me notice a couple of things.
不 你的攻击让我注意到很多事
Like what?
很多事？
The places you stabbed would've been fatal for a human,
你所刺的地方对人类来说都是致命伤
but not for my sister.
但对我妹妹来说却不是
This means either that she doesn't have vital organs there,
也就是说 那些部分并没有重要的脏器
or she has more somewhere else.
或是存在多个内脏
A bunch of monsters like the Basilisk, Cerberus, and Scylla have multiple brains.
像巴西利斯克、克尔柏洛斯、斯库拉 多数魔物有复数个大脑
It's pretty common in Chimera types.
在奇美拉类型中很常见
His pupils are dilated.
他瞳孔都打开了
He must really love monsters.
看来是真的很喜欢魔物
So his knowledge is his weapon.
这些知识就是他的武器啊
He says he'll defeat the lunatic magician.
他说要打倒迷宫之主
There are plenty of adventurers more skilled than him,
比他有能力的冒险者确实有很多
but none with his level of knowledge and motivation.
但没有人有这么多的知识和动机
This guy might just pull it off.
他搞不好真的能做到
But
然而…
what happens after he defeats the lord of the dungeon?
打倒了迷宫之主之后呢？
They say whoever takes down the lunatic magician
听说打倒狂乱魔术师的人
will gain everything in the kingdom.
可以得到这个国家的一切
What if that means becoming the next lord of the dungeon?
如果那就相当于 他会成为下一任迷宫之主的话呢？
What will he do with this city built by black magic and all its monsters
一旦获得了黑魔法创造的都市 以及所有的魔物
when he inherits them?
这男人会怎么做？
Will he quietly seal the dungeon?
会干脆地封印这座迷宫吗？
Aren't you hungry?
你饿不饿？
Huh?
什么？
HARPY EGG OMELET
（哈比蛋玉子烧）
What's this?
这是什么？
It's an omelet made from a Harpy egg.
用哈比蛋做的玉子烧
Senshi found an egg earlier.
刚刚先西找到了蛋
You seemed interested in monster cuisine,
因为你看起来 对魔物料理有兴趣的样子
so have one.
吃一个吧
Mother!
妈妈！
I'd rather die than eat it!
我死都不想吃！
What do I do? How do I get out of this?
怎么办？要怎么糊弄过去？
No, maybe I have no choice but to kill him now.
不 我只能当场杀掉他吧
Not now!
现在做不到！
I'll try one!
我开动了！
Typical of Kabru.
真不愧是他
He'll do anything to win someone's favor.
为了赢得对方的心 他什么都做得到
What a nice guy.
他人真好
The return magic is ready.
回归魔法已经准备好了
No one is injured, yes?
没有受伤的人吧？
Beyond this portal is the surface.
再往前就是地面了
If you die there, we can't bring you back.
死了可就不能复活了
To be honest,
老实说啊
I think you'll die before you even get to the lunatic magician.
我认为你可能会在 找到狂乱魔术师前就翘辫子
But if you do manage to survive,
但如果你活了下来
but can't make it back to the surface because of black magic,
却因黑魔法而不能回地上
ring this bell.
到时候就摇响这个
It'll resonate with its twin far away.
它和另一个离很远的铃是一对的 会互相共鸣
I'll send an escort to help you flee to the east.
我会派人帮助你逃到东方
Don't die.
别死啊
Thanks.
谢谢
Laios,
莱欧斯
I'm glad we got to chat.
能跟你谈到话真是太好了
That was the highlight of this trip for me.
这是我这次最大的收获
The pleasure is mine.
我也是
Um…
那个…
Quickly now.
快点啦
You remember my name now, right?
你记得我的名字对吧？
Huh? Of course.
什么？当然啊
Good.
那就好
Don't forget next time.
下次可别忘了
Well, see you.
我走了 再见
Next time?
“下次”？
Let's go, Laios!
该走了 莱欧斯！
There's no turning back now.
我们不能回头了
Crap. See?
可恶 看吧
I just knew this was going to happen in the end.
我早就有事情会变成这样的预感了
Crap!
该死啊！
That's vulgar, Chil.
太粗俗了 奇尔
I'm sorry.
抱歉
It'll all work out somehow.
总会有办法解决的
Subtitle translation by: Ai Matsuoka
字幕翻译：柯欣冉